<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>digital-creations</title>
    <link>https://digcre.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on digital-creations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; 2023 Daniel Knobloch</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://digcre.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Use traefik certificate enrolment with IONOS certificates</title>
      <link>https://digcre.io/post/2023/2023-07-10-traefik-reverse-proxy-with-ionos-certificates/</link>
      
      <guid>https://digcre.io/post/2023/2023-07-10-traefik-reverse-proxy-with-ionos-certificates/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I use traefik reverse proxy as the entrypoint for all my docker container services to have proper SSL termination. To enrol my certificates I use the development API for IONOS to solve the dns-challenge and hand it over to the resolver to request a new certificate when I create a new service.
What is covered or what is the TL;DR here ? We use a Kubernetes Cluster to deploy KAN into it and use the ready to use AI Skills to connect our Videostream from the camera to detect vehicles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-deploy apps on your workstation with ease</title>
      <link>https://digcre.io/post/2023/2023-07-18-redeploy-your-machine-with-ease/</link>
      
      <guid>https://digcre.io/post/2023/2023-07-18-redeploy-your-machine-with-ease/</guid>
      <description>Introduction With the release of version 1.5 of Winget we can finally add multiple app names in one install/uninstall command. Now we dont need to create powershell scripts to run the winget command multiple times for each action and app again.
Implementation If youre running Windows 11 you already have winget installed, on Windows 10 you can get it via store.
You can verify installation via winget -v for version and winget &amp;ndash;info for generic information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using KubeAI Application Nucleus for edge (KAN)</title>
      <link>https://digcre.io/post/2023/2023-06-25-using-kubeai-nucleus-for-edge/</link>
      
      <guid>https://digcre.io/post/2023/2023-06-25-using-kubeai-nucleus-for-edge/</guid>
      <description>Using KubeAI Application Nucleus for edge Introduction I have a real world scenario requirement to implement an environmental sensor to count vehicles driving infront of my balcony. To do this my inital idea was to set up a camera and attach it to a Coral/TPU powered Rasperry Pi to catch the stream from the camera and count vehicles.
As we all know, RPis and also TPUs arent available and anything then a good deal at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create high-quality GIFs from recorded videos</title>
      <link>https://digcre.io/post/2023/2023-05-03-create-high-quality-gifs-from-mp4-files/</link>
      
      <guid>https://digcre.io/post/2023/2023-05-03-create-high-quality-gifs-from-mp4-files/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Very often I need to embed videos into my documentation or wiki articles. Due the fact that plain MP4 files arent support and even make no sense in a wiki, I needed a solution to have a quick and easy solution. For this we get use of ffmpeg and convert our file from MP4 to GIF. Especially when you want to show high quality videos, you should add a palette as input to improve the output gif.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://digcre.io/pages/projects/</link>
      
      <guid>https://digcre.io/pages/projects/</guid>
      <description>Overview of current projects Technology Description Link Proxmox &amp;amp; VMs Read Docker Enable hw transcoding for a plex docker container Read Tasmota </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://digcre.io/pages/impressum/</link>
      
      <guid>https://digcre.io/pages/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Impressum Contact via Mail: info@digcre.io
Haftungsausschluss: Haftung für Inhalte Die Inhalte unserer Seiten wurden mit größter Sorgfalt erstellt. Für die Richtigkeit, Vollständigkeit und Aktualität der Inhalte können wir jedoch keine Gewähr übernehmen. Als Diensteanbieter sind wir gemäß § 7 Abs.1 TMG für eigene Inhalte auf diesen Seiten nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen verantwortlich. Nach §§ 8 bis 10 TMG sind wir als Diensteanbieter jedoch nicht verpflichtet, übermittelte oder gespeicherte fremde Informationen zu überwachen oder nach Umständen zu forschen, die auf eine rechtswidrige Tätigkeit hinweisen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://digcre.io/pages/about/</link>
      
      <guid>https://digcre.io/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, I&amp;rsquo;m Daniel and this is my personal blog to note down my daily tech adventures and proof-of-concept stunts :-)
Hope you enjoy your visit, and if you have any questions disqurs is enabled.
Located in Europe &amp;gt; Germany &amp;gt; Dresden
Florence, Italy Dubai, UAE </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Plex in Docker with Hardware Transcoding</title>
      <link>https://digcre.io/post/2022/2022-12-23-plex-on-docker-with-hw-transcoding/</link>
      
      <guid>https://digcre.io/post/2022/2022-12-23-plex-on-docker-with-hw-transcoding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Post describes how to set up Plex in a Docker Container while using the hw transcoding functionality from my Quadro GPU and the nVidia Toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detect Proxmox hardware unit hang</title>
      <link>https://digcre.io/post/2022/2022-01-05-detect-hardware-unit-hang/</link>
      
      <guid>https://digcre.io/post/2022/2022-01-05-detect-hardware-unit-hang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I had some issues with the reliability of my local network connections from the proxmox host and their services. This came up with application crashes on a Windows 11 VM where explorer.exe restarted every time I connected to this VM via RDP or Plex started buffering the stream in random situations. Turns out this was due the reset of the built-in network card on the proxmox host itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>